# Derek Misler Developer & Designer

derekmisler.com ★ derekmisler.github.io ★ 828-273-6943 ★ derekmisler@gmail.com

I am a front-end developer and UI/UX designer living in New York with 10+ years experience. I have a diverse education, both traditional and self-driven, of many different web and application development languages for both desktop and mobile. I am basically fluent when it comes to HTML5, CSS3 (including CSS preprocessors like LESS and Sass) along with JavaScript/jQuery (including frameworks like Angular and React). I have experience with back-end and software languages, too, like C# and .NET, Node, Python, Ruby, and a long history with PHP. I also have a design background a surprisingly large knowledge of typography (seriously, let's talk about it). I think all developers should study design, and I believe having this well-rounded education makes me a stronger developer. For more experience information and contact details, as well as a portfolio of work, visit derekmisler.com or derekmisler.github.io.

#### Career

## Asheville Convention & Visitors Bureau

Web Manager 2011–2015

As the only developer on staff, my job was to maintain our entire web presence. Starting with a .NET-backed site, I oversaw two redesigns: first a Coldfusion site and more recently with a responsive site that was developed primarily in Node.js on the back-end and a custom JS framework, Goatee, on the front-end. I also developed two long-form, award-winning web apps.

## **Houser Shoes, Inc.**

Designer/Developer/Photographer 2010-2011

I was part of a 3 person team that redesigned their e-commerce website. We also created a custom CMS based on Magento, which utilized primarily PHP and MySQL and was tied to their inventory and accounting systems.

## **Education**

# **Appalachian State University**

BFA - Graphic Design 2005-

I chose to study graphic design in an arts department. I already had a grasp on front-end web development techniques and continued to study them during this time, but the curriculum path I chose focused on web design while also teaching color theory, typography, and layout design in a group setting.

### **Freelance**

Designer/Developer

2009-Present

A lot of branding, especially at first, but I eventually had enough clients needing new websites that I became a full-time web developer. A lot of HTML/CSS/JavaScript and PHP (usually Wordpress).

# **Precision Printing**

Designer/Printer

2007-2009

Though this isn't web-related, I still think my experience working in a print shop can be seen in my work as a developer.

# The Appalachian Newspaper

Lead Designer/Developer

2006-2008

I worked with an intern to establish an online presence for the newspaper, while still maintaining my role as the lead graphic designer.

## Skills

Adobe CS	****	JavaScript	****
HTML5/CSS3	****	jQuery	****
LESS/Sass	****	Angular/Jekyll	****
PHP	***	Git/Github	****
C#/.NET	***	React/JSX	****
C/C++	***	Python	****
ColdFusion	***	Ruby	***
Node	***	Java	***